<?xml version="1.0"?>
<tool id="picard-CreateSequenceDictionary" name="picard-CreateSequenceDictionary" version="0.1.0" python_template_version="3.5">
    <requirements>
        <container type="docker">cnag/picard:2.18.25</container>
    </requirements>
    <command detect_errors="exit_code"><![CDATA[
        #set $localref = 'reference.fa'
        ln -s '$reference' '$localref' &&
        java -jar /opt/picard/2.18.25/picard.jar CreateSequenceDictionary  R=$localref O=tempfile &&
        mv tempfile $output
    ]]></command>
    <inputs>
        <param type="data" name="reference" format="fasta" label="Reference Genome"/>
    </inputs>
    <outputs>
        <data name="output" format="sam" label="Reference Genome dictionary"/>
    </outputs>
    <help><![CDATA[

R=reference.fasta \
O=reference.dict


Version: 2.18.25-SNAPSHOT


Options:

--help
-h                            Displays options specific to this tool.

--stdhelp
-H                            Displays options specific to this tool AND options common to all Picard command line
                              tools.

--version                     Displays program version.

OUTPUT=File
O=File                        Output SAM file containing only the sequence dictionary. By default it will use the base
                              name of the input reference with the .dict extension  Default value: null.

GENOME_ASSEMBLY=String
AS=String                     Put into AS field of sequence dictionary entry if supplied  Default value: null.

URI=String
UR=String                     Put into UR field of sequence dictionary entry.  If not supplied, input reference file is
                              used  Default value: null.

SPECIES=String
SP=String                     Put into SP field of sequence dictionary entry  Default value: null.

TRUNCATE_NAMES_AT_WHITESPACE=Boolean
                              Make sequence name the first word from the > line in the fasta file.  By default the
                              entire contents of the > line is used, excluding leading and trailing whitespace.  Default
                              value: true. This option can be set to 'null' to clear the default value. Possible values:
                              {true, false}

NUM_SEQUENCES=Integer         Stop after writing this many sequences.  For testing.  Default value: 2147483647. This
                              option can be set to 'null' to clear the default value.

ALT_NAMES=File
AN=File                       Optional file containing the alternative names for the contigs. Tools may use this
                              information to consider different contig notations as identical (e.g: 'chr1' and '1'). The
                              alternative names will be put into the appropriate @AN annotation for each contig. No
                              header. First column is the original name, the second column is an alternative name. One
                              contig may have more than one alternative name.  Default value: null.

REFERENCE=File
R=File                        Input reference fasta or fasta.gz  Required.
    ]]></help>
<citations>
    <citation type="bibtex">@misc{Picard,
            author = {Broad Institute},
            title = {Picard},
            publisher = {GitHub},
            journal = { Broad Institute, GitHub repository},
            url = {http://broadinstitute.github.io/picard/}
        }
    </citation>
 </citations> 
</tool>
